Eighty-five. Pros and cons of coffee. Our relationship with coffee is complicated.
Some people say they can't get up in the morning without it. Other people believe it's practically deadly.
When it comes to coffee, there are a lot of pros and cons.
Here are a few of the pros. For one, coffee can be good for your body and your mind.
The caffeine in coffee, the chemical that wakes you up, might help prevent diabetes and Alzheimer's disease in the long term.
In the short term, caffeine can improve mental performance and help with breathing problems.
Coffee is also full of a kind of vitamin which protects the cells in your body.
Other vitamins in it can help stop signs of aging and even prevent some cancers.
In tests, coffee has also been shown to prevent Parkinson's disease, kidney stones, and liver problems.
What could be bad about a drink like that? Well, on the flip side, coffee seems to cause or contribute to a lot of other diseases.
It can raise cholesterol in the body and it's not good for your blood circulation.
Coffee, as you have probably seen, can make you excited and nervous. It raises people's heart rates and, sometimes, blood pressure, which is dangerous.
It also may cause you to lose water and feel thirsty. It may be bad for your bones, especially for women.
There are even some studies that connect drinking coffee with heart disease.
So, how can you decide if you should drink coffee? Consider your own circumstances.
If you have a bad heart or high blood pressure, stay away from it.
However, if you need to be sharp and you want to prevent some other diseases later in life, a cup of coffee in the morning probably won't hurt.